ANDREW NOONAN

andrew@noonan.cc | 215-292-5083

SUMMARY

Over 10 years of experience as an engineer, manager, and technical lead at companies ranging from 20 to 30,000+ people. Recently I have worked as lead for large scale projects serving as both product and engineering leadership; working with internal and external cross-functional teams to architect, build, and bring products to market. I am interested in capitalizing on my diverse experience to build and execute a product roadmap with a small and agile team.

SKILLS

Software Engineering, Systems Architecture, API Design Product Management & Development, Project Management Java, Python, NodeJS, C++, SQL, Cassandra, Redis, Lucene, Kafka

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

NOVEMBER 2015 - JANUARY 2020

Technical Lead Manager | Senior Partner Engineer, Uber

- As tech lead and system architect, delivered Uber Money's banking product to market under aggressive deadlines
- Lead engineering effort for \$3.7 Billion merger with Yandex.taxi in Russia
- Delivered react native copy of the Uber rider app in Russia to ~10 million users in under 10 months managing a cross functional team of internal and external stakeholders
- Designed and launched Uber/Google Maps integration to 20+ million riders
- Co-designed Google OpenID connect protocol for use with Google Maps integration

JANUARY 2015 - NOVEMBER 2015

Head of Partner Engineering, Asana

- Fostered relationships with large organizations such as Slack and Atlassian to extend Asana's product reach through integrations
- Prioritized engineering and product asks from external partners
- Worked closely with the CEO and other leaders in the company to prioritize internal and external product roadmaps to enable integrations

MAY 2014 - JANUARY 2015

Senior Partner Engineer, Twitter

- Design and launch mobile attribution APIs and platform for Twitter ads
- Managed technical relationships with all major industry mobile ads tracking platforms
- Developed internal tooling to bring integrations to market faster

Head of Partner Engineering | Software Engineer, Gnip

- Developed business plan for and launched Partner Engineering team at Gnip
- Increased revenue of strategic partnerships by 40% in some cases through technical optimizations and tighter product feedback loops
- Developed a highly concurrent backend web application in Java and RoR for processing streams of social media data in real time
- Leveraged Kafka queues to build a reliable and flexible data processing infrastructure
- Designed and implemented geo location and language detection algorithms with >20,000 rps

SEPTEMBER 2009 - DECEMBER 2011

Software Engineer, Lockheed Martin

- Co-developed award winning geospatial functionality on a tactical display framework in Java
- Engineering lead for an access control system refactoring for group based authorization of backend applications to prevent impact of system compromises
- Engineered a DoD approved TCP/IP packet based communication between C++ and Java applications similar to Google protobuf
- Held a Top Secret clearance from the United States Department of Defense

EDUCATION

Graduated 2009

Bachelor of Science, University of Colorado at Boulder - Boulder, Colorado

Computer Science Engineering major, Computer Engineering minor

- Engineering and Applied Science Dean's List
- Elected President of the Engineering School